Cos Cob Power Plant Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Cos Cob Power Plant Records.
undated, 1891-1986.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Cos Cob Power Plant (Conn.).
18 linear feet.
The Cos Cob Power Plant, an electrical power plant located in Greenwich, Connecticut, was part of a pioneering venture in mainline railroad electrification. With the Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company, the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad designed an efficient system using alternating-current (ac) electrification that facilitated railroad traffic into urban areas after the New York legislature passed laws prohibiting the use of steam locomotives in New York City south of the Harlem River. Construction of the Cos Cob Power Plant was completed in 1907 and served as the generating station for power to the trains. The collection consists of blueprints and wiring diagrams for the electrical systems of the Woodlawn, New York, to New Haven, Connecticut, line, with architectural drawings, foremen's log books, records of coal received, and administrative correspondence.
MSS19880024
History
The Cos Cob Power Plant was conceived in 1903 as a result of the New York State legislature’s law that prohibited all steam locomotives from entering New York City after 1908 due to train wrecks in the Park Avenue Tunnel caused by low visibility from locomotive smoke and steam. The New York Central Railroad, which operated all railroad traffic between Woodlawn, New York, into New York City, decided to install a low-voltage direct current third-rail electrical system; thus after 1908 all locomotives coming into New York City's Grand Central Terminal (then under construction), would be forced to operate off third- rail.
Although the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, better known as the New Haven Railroad, operated considerable low- voltage direct current trackage at this time, this system was considered inadequate for the operation of heavy trains over long distances at high speeds. The New Haven Railroad’s engineers, working with Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company of Pennsylvania, decided to install high-voltage 11,000 volt overhead wires on the tracks from Woodlawn, New York, into Connecticut. These wires would be powered from the railroad's own power station, using single-phase alternating current (ac) electricity. This was done at a time when low-voltage direct current electrification was the rail standard of the day.
Construction of the power plant began in 1905 in Cos Cob, Connecticut, located in the town of Greenwich on the Mianus River. On 24 July 1907, the first New Haven Railroad electrified passenger train traveled from Grand Central Terminal to New Rochelle, New York. The initial electrification covered all four tracks to Stamford, Connecticut, and in 1913-1914 was extended to New Haven, Connecticut.
The New York Central Railroad's third-rail system from Woodlawn, New York, into Grand Central Terminal required the New Haven Railroad's locomotives to operate both off this system and on their own high-voltage overhead wire. This meant that these locomotives and multiple unit cars had to change over between these two systems while moving at track speed. With so much traffic it was considered unworkable to stop every train for the changeover.
The initial overhead catenary construction from Woodlawn to Stamford utilized two parallel messenger wires supporting a single trolley wire by vertical hangers, resulting in a triangular construction. The rigidity of this arrangement was found to be undesireable, so the 1913-1914 electrification extension to New Haven utilized a single messenger wire, as did other extensions. The system reached 673 track miles at its maximum.
The Cos Cob Power Plant was the first power plant built exclusively for a railroad and is considered an engineering achievement for its use of high-voltage alternating current (ac) for railroad electrification. The plant served the New Haven Railroad until the railroad's demise in 1969, and then served Penn Central, Conrail and Metro-North until it was closed in 1986. The Cos Cob Power Plant received landmark status from the American Society of Mechanical Engineers/Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers in 1982.
Scope and Content
The records consist of blueprints and wiring diagrams for the electrical systems of the electrified railroad zone of Woodlawn, New York, to Cedar Hill in New Haven, Connecticut, that provided power to the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, generated by the Cos Cob Power Plant. The records also include architectural drawings, foremen's log books, records of coal received, and administrative correspondence concerning the power plant and the Mianus River Dam.
Arrangement
Series I: Blueprints and other documents ( 1912-1966 ) of anchor bridges and electrification along the New Haven Railroad shoreline route from New York City to Cedar Hill in New Haven, Connecticut,. Materials in this series are organized by anchor bridges (or electric girders which support the catenary wire that transmits the electricity) situated along the electrified railroad zone.
Series II: Historical information about electrification along the New Haven Railroad ( 1891-1982 ) provides information about the equipment and structures serviced and the processes that were made possible through the Cos Cob Power Plant, mostly in its first several years of function.
Series III: Boiler office records concerning machinery ( undated, 1915-1986 ) give detailed information about the servicing of equipment through the boiler office of the plant.
Series IV: Boiler office files ( undated, 1921-1985 ) consist of manuals, catalogs, and instructions for boilers and circuit breakers, as well as correspondence, inventories, blueprints, and other documents with information about environmental pollution and emissions monitoring, labor unions for the railroad personnel, and specifications for switchboards, cable, and transformers. Also includes photographs of exterior and interior scenes of the plant and its equipment, as well as the Mianus pumping station and company executives. Alphabetically by topic.
Series V: Boiler office log sheets and repair records ( 1926-1986 ) show regular service and repair notes for the boiler room, coal received, the operations foreman, and electric meter field tests.
Series VI: Power plant architectural plans (rolled plans) ( undated ) show maps of the power plant property and plans and details of the power plant facilities and the Mianus River Dam.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of records pertaining to New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Railroads--Electrification.; Electric railroads-–Connecticut-–Substations.; Electrical power plants–-Connecticut-–Cos Cob.; Railroads-–Power supply-–Connecticut.; Electric circuits-–Alternating currents.; Cos Cob Power Plant (Conn.); Cos Cob (Conn.); Connecticut--Business, industries, and trades--Electric industry.; Cos Cob (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades--Electric industry.; Mianus River Dam (Conn.)
Organizations:
Penn Central Transportation Company.; New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Company.; Westinghouse Electric Corporation.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Blueprints.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Press releases.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Manuscripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Books.; Scrap-Books.; Inventories.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The records were stored in the power plant facility in Cos Cob, Connecticut, prior to the donation to the University of Connecticut.
Acquisition Information
The Cos Cob Power Plant Records were transferred from the Connecticut Department of Transportation to the University of Connecticut Libraries in August 1988 and March 1991.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Blueprints and other documents, 1912-1966
  - Harlem River Branch - General: electrification information, blueprints, wire locations, instructions, costs, 1948 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Bowery Bay Substation: proposals, operating instructions, blueprints, 1942-1949 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Bowery Bay Substation - Plans: electrification information, diagrams, blueprints, 1946-1956 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Oak Point, NY: blueprints, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Oak Point Yard, NY: diagrams, blueprints, 1912-1948 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Oak Point, NY: diagrams, blueprints, diagrams, operating instructions, 1941-1948 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Oak Point, NY: blueprints, 1947-1949 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - West Farms, NY - General: testing procedures, diagrams, blueprints, proposals, correspondence, instructions, printed material, 1943-1957 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - West Farms, NY Substation: drawing index, equipment, material specs, 1937-1952 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - West Farms, NY Substation: testing records and procedures, relay test manuals, diagrams, blueprints, 1949-1953 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - West Farms, NY: blueprints, diagrams, 1916-1951 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - West Farms, NY: blueprints, diagrams, 1946-1957 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - West Farms, NY: purchasers order, diagrams, blueprints, 1914-1957 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Pelham Bay, NY: operating instructions, blueprints, diagrams, 1945-1966 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Pelham Bay Draw Bridge, NY diagrams, blueprints, drawings, instructions, 1937-1941 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - New Rochelle Junction, NY: operation instructions, drawings, corresondence, diagrams, blueprints, 1936-1956 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - New Rochelle Junction, NY: diagrams, blueprints, 1928-1978 (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - South Mount Vernon, NY: charts, correspondence, drawings, instructions, blueprints, diagrams, 1941-1948 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - New Rochelle, NY: purchasers orders, blueprints, operation instructions, diagrams, 1945-1966 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - New Rochelle, NY: purchasers orders, blueprints, 1946-1957 (Box 3:, Folder 20)
  - Rye, NY: blueprints, diagrams, 1941-1943 (Box 3:, Folder 21)
  - Port Chester, NY: blueprints, 1945 (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - East Port Chester, NY: blueprints, diagrams, notes, 1940-1943 (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - Greenwich, CT: diagrams, blueprints, notes, 1940-1942 (Box 3:, Folder 24)
  - Cos Cob, CT: blueprints, diagrams, correspondence, 1942-1949 (Box 3:, Folder 25)
  - Riverside (Greenwich), CT: notes, blueprints, 1945 (Box 3:, Folder 26)
  - Stamford, CT: notes, diagrams, blueprints, 1942 (Box 3:, Folder 27)
  - New Canaan, CT Branch - General: reports, 1954 (Box 3:, Folder 28)
  - Darien, CT: diagrams, blueprints, operating instructions, correspondence, notes, 1939-1966 (Box 3:, Folder 29)
  - Darien, CT: correspondence, material transfer/issue tickets, notes, daily work reports and time records, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 30)
  - South Norwalk, CT: test records, diagrams, blueprints, notes, 1925-1945 (Box 3:, Folder 31)
  - South Norwalk (Drawbridge), CT: electrification blueprints, notes, 1945 (Box 3:, Folder 32)
  - Danbury, CT Branch - General: diagrams, blueprints, purchaser orders, correspondence, Westinghouse Electric Corporation memos, 1926-1955 (Box 3:, Folder 33)
  - Greens Farms, CT: Westinghouse proposals and specifications, purchasers orders, operating instructions, diagrams, blueprints, 1915-1950 (Box 3:, Folder 34)
  - Burr Road: blueprints, 1950 (Box 3:, Folder 35)
  - Bridgeport, CT: blueprints, diagrams, 1947 (Box 3:, Folder 36)
  - Devon, CT: blueprints, diagrams, material list, notes, instructions, purchasers orders, 1928-1955 (Box 3:, Folder 37)
  - Woodmont, CT (signals): correspondence, blueprints, 1953-1954 (Box 4:, Folder 38)
  - Woodmont, CT (capacitors): correspondence, instructions, Westinghouse publications, specifications, drawings, purchase orders, test reports, diagrams, 1945-1948 (Box 4:, Folder 39)
  - Woodmont, CT (capacitors): reports, proposals, correspondence, diagrams, 1949-1964 (Box 4:, Folder 40)
  - Woodmont, CT: diagrams, blueprints, drawing index, 1945-1950 (Box 4:, Folder 41)
  - Woodmont, CT: blueprints, drawings index, 1949-1954 (Box 4:, Folder 42)
  - Woodmont, CT: purchasers orders, drawings, blueprints, 1942-1948 (Box 4:, Folder 43)
  - New Haven, CT: electrification blueprints, 1921 (Box 4:, Folder 44)
  - Cedar Street, New Haven, CT: diagrams, blueprints, purchasers orders, drawings index, 1945-1957 (Box 4:, Folder 45)
  - Cedar Street, New Haven, CT: notes, drawings, operating instructions, proposals, diagrams, blueprints, 1945-1946 (Box 4:, Folder 46)
  - Fair Street, New Haven, CT: notes, operating instructions, memos, drawings, requisitions, correspondence, proposals, diagrams, blueprints, 1918-1955 (Box 5:, Folder 47)
  - Fair Street, New Haven, CT: purchasers orders, notes, diagrams, blueprints, 1940-1960 (Box 5:, Folder 48)
  - Mill River Junction, New Haven, CT: blueprints, 1915-1949 (Box 5:, Folder 49)
  - Cedar Hill, New Haven, CT: sectionalizing maps, correspondence, proposals, electrification diagrams, blueprints, 1934-1957 (Box 5:, Folder 50)
  - Cedar Hill, New Haven, CT: purchasers orders, blueprints, 1953-1956 (Box 5:, Folder 51)
- Series II: Historical information, 1891-1982
  - Cos Cob (Dispatcher): memos, operating instructions, Westinghouse publications, diagrams, blueprints, 1938-1943 (Box 5:, Folder 52)
  - Cos Cob (Dispatcher): blueprints, 1940-1951 (Box 5:, Folder 53)
  - Cos Cob (Dispatcher): drawings index, wiring diagrams, blueprints, 1939-1957 (Box 5:, Folder 54)
  - Cos Cob (Dispatcher): diagrams, blueprints, 1939-1953 (Box 5:, Folder 55)
  - “New Haven Electrification”: article by Sy Reich, 1975 (Box 6:, Folder 56)
  - Historical: map, electrification blueprints, proposal, 1891-1943 (Box 6:, Folder 57)
  - Structural: blueprints, 1922-1924 (Box 6:, Folder 58)
  - Power System (11-25kv): electrification blueprints, wiring diagrams, 1914-1947 (Box 6:, Folder 59)
  - 11KV/22KV. 3-Wire System Showing Power Connections, 1946
  - Hell Gate - West Farms Connections, 1938
  - West Farms to Bay Ridge 11-KV Power System Operating Diagram (390EE-73-1), 1944, revised 1947
  - General Distribution Diagram for All Lines West of Cos Cob, 1914
  - Main Wiring Diagram - Cos Cob Power Station (3845), 1921
  - Power Plant Equipment - Electrical Plans: blueprints, diagrams, 1921-1954 (Box 6:, Folder 60)
  - Main Structure Diagram (6S-1001), 1928
  - “MC” Temper. & “CO” Relay Brd. Wiring Diagram, rear view (6S-1005), 1928
  - Recording Meter Board Wiring Diagram, rear view (6S-1006), 1928
  - Bench Board Writing Diagram, rear view (6S-1007), 1928
  - Instrument Board Wiring Diagram, rear view (6S-1008), 1928
  - 60∼ Signal Board Wiring Diagram, rear view (6S-1009), 1928
  - Diff. Proj. & Battery Floating SW Board Wiring Diagram (6D-1010), 1928
  - Load Totalizing (389-109), 1945
  - Operating Wiring Diagram (550E-6), 1945
  - Station Recording Meter Panel, rear view (550E-7), 1945
  - 440V Switchgear Control Conduits (550-E-36), 1945
  - 440 Volt Power Conduits at Switchgear (550-E-37), 1945
  - 22 KV. Electrical Assembly Sections (550-E-63), 1945
  - 22 K.V. O.C.B. Disconnecting Switch Grounding Details (550-E-66), 1945
  - Proposed Wiring Diagram for Operating Supervisory Lamps on AC at Cos Cob (5809-2), 1950
  - 11KV & 22KV Operating Wiring Diagram, 1952; (2 copies),
  - Testing: blueprints, test reports, diagrams, drawings, notes, correspondence, 1937-1949 (Box 6:, Folder 61)
  - Circuit Breaker Rehab: blueprints, diagrams, notes, ca. 1943 (Box 6:, Folder 62)
  - Electrical Parts/Plans: survey reports, blueprints, correspondence, notes, memos, diagrams, instructions, 1922-1957 (Box 6:, Folder 63)
  - Electrical Parts/Plans: blueprints, diagrams, 1927-1947 (Box 6:, Folder 64)
  - Electrical Parts/Catalogs: publications, instructions, catalogs, 1933-1949 (Box 6:, Folder 65)
  - Battery Systems: diagrams, blueprints, notes, memos, 1942 (Box 6:, Folder 66)
  - Signals: blueprints, diagrams, 1922-1954 (Box 6:, Folder 67)
  - Signal circuits, Line West of Cos Cob, 1922
  - Signal circuits, Line West of Cos Cob, 1954 (revision)
  - Harlem River Branch Electrification, Signal Circuit Sectionalizing on Bridge 41-H, 1929
  - Providence Signal Power Substation, Schematic Diagram -- Front View Drawing, 1929
  - Wiring Diagram, 440V Signal Switchgear, SS-22 New Rochelle Junction, New York, 1946
  - Proposed Signal Power Changes at New Rochelle, 1936
  - Proposed Signal Circuits on Harlem River Branch, 1928
  - Proposed Re-arrangement of Signal Circuits & Apparatus at Tower 22 - New Rochelle, 1923
  - Operating Wiring Diagram (550E-6), 1945
  - United Illuminating Co., Signal Power Supply Structure Diagram, 1941
  - Anchor Bridges (AB) and Catenary (Gen'l): list of bridges, blueprints, diagrams, 1906-1949 (Box 6:, Folder 68)
  - Steel Details of Cross Arms for Signal Change, Northside, Harlem River Branch, 1949
  - Norwalk Tunnel, Steel Details for Proposed Revision to Catenary Supports, undated
  - Electrification Cost Data, 1928
  - Woodlawn - Stamford Electrification -- Typical Double Catenary Construction on Tangent, 1921
  - Elevation Showing Construction Between Bridges, undated
  - List of Catenary Bridges, From New York State Line to Stamford, Connecticut, 1906
  - List of Bridges (by number), Stations (by number), "Regular" and "Special", undated
  - Electrification Platford for Transformers TP #10 - New Haven Yard, undated
  - Line Construction Direct Suspension, Glass Trough for Overhead Insulation, 1943
  - Yard Catenary Construction, undated
  - Modified Arrangements of Control Wiring for Anchor Bridges No. 72 to No. 374 Inclusive, undated
  - Standard Bridge Manhole for 4 ducts or less, undated
  - Showing Marking of Manhole Cover for Electric Trains, 1933
  - Electrification, Main Bridge Construction, 1911
  - List of bridges (by number), stations (by number), cross section, span C to C, Number of TRs, Curve, EL hose of Steel from top of rail, Truss, North post, South post, cross-arm support, etc., for Glenbrook Electrication, undated
  - Catenary - Materials, Procedures, Construction: blueprints, diagrams, materials catalog, 1920-1953 (Box 6:, Folder 69)
  - Parts with numbers and drawing numbers (presumably for catenary), undated
  - 3/4" U-Bolts
  - Chart for Bending Hangers and Threading Ends
  - Splice Plate for 3" J-Beam
  - Proposed Ties for Pin Insulators
  - Tangent Hanger Rod Lengths
  - Weights of Poles and Catenary Bridges
  - Vertical Insulator on Reg. Int. Catenary Bridge
  - Steel Plate Yoke for dead-ending double strain insulators
  - Assembly of Double Catenary Trolley Hangers
  - Details of Spreader and Hanger
  - Angle Iron Saddle for Pin Type Insulators
  - Porcelain Suspension Insulator: Locke nos. 10100, 18158
  - Type "Z0" Insulator (Switch and Bus)
  - Insulator - Switch and Bus Type, 1947
  - Operations, Environmental (Air Quality, Noise): correspondence, DEP reports, 1980 (Box 6:, Folder 70)
  - Personnel- Instructional: manuals, 1927-1982 (Box 6:, Folder 71)
- Series III: Boiler office records, undated, 1915-1986
  - 7200 KVA Transformer: notes, receipts, diagrams, correspondence, printed materials, ca. 1946 (Box 7:, Folder 72)
  - Outgoing Switches (Gallery): blueprints, invoices, 1924-1946 (Box 7:, Folder 73)
  - Signal Generators: correspondence, notes, drawings, 1939-1954 (Box 7:, Folder 74)
  - Exciter G: specification reports, diagrams, drawings, 1922-1953 (Box 7:, Folder 75)
  - Signal Exciters: instructions, correspondence, diagrams, invoices, materials lists, diagrams, 1915, 1976, 1979 (Box 7:, Folder 76)
  - 440 Volt Panels: notes, blueprints, various dates (Box 7:, Folder 77)
  - Battery - Charging Sets DC / Circuits Station Control Batteries: correspondence, test records, instructions, publications, drawings, 1945-1969 (Box 7:, Folder 78)
  - Battery - Charging Sets DC / Circuits Boiler Room: drawings, notes, undated (Box 7:, Folder 79)
  - Battery - Charging Sets / DC Circuits Battery Charging Set: operating instructions, installation instructions, printed material, blueprints, drawings, 1936-1948 (Box 7:, Folder 80)
  - Battery - Charging Sets / DC Circuits BC Charging Set: publications, installation instructions, operating instructions, specifications, correspondence, diagrams, packing lists, notes, receipts, 1944-1947 (Box 7:, Folder 81)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus New Electrical Air Compressor: instructions, notes, 1973 (Box 7:, Folder 82)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus #1 Air Conditioner (3 Ton) - New: installation instructions, service data, publications, correspondence, warranties, diagrams, service manuals, 1955-1965 (Box 7:, Folder 83)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus #2 Air Conditioner (7 ½ Ton) - Old: notes, publications, contracts, correspondence, invoices, blueprints, printed material, warranties, drawings, installations instructions, service instructions, 1945-1952 (Box 7:, Folder 84)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Condensers: diagrams, 1956 (Box 7:, Folder 85)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Hot Well Pump: drawings, notes, correspondence, instructions invoices, 1946 (Box 7:, Folder 86)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Pipe Threading Machine: packing slip, instructions, 1939 (Box 7:, Folder 87)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Service Water Pump: correspondence, publications, drawings, instructions, notes, 1936-1986 (Box 7:, Folder 88)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Syntron Vibrators: blueprints, diagrams, correspondence, notes, price lists, publications, instructions, business cards, notes, various dates (Box 7:, Folder 89)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Welding Machine: publications, 1939 (Box 7:, Folder 90)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus Auxiliary Oil System: diagrams, undated (Box 7:, Folder 91)
  - Auxiliary Apparatus MG Set and Silverstat: diagrams, instructions, publications, blueprints, diagrams, notes, memos, correspondence, specifications, 1947 (Box 7:, Folder 92)
  - Crane: notes, drawings, blueprintsnotes, drawings, blueprints, undated (Box 7:, Folder 93)
  - Boiler 900: parts publication, 1943 (Box 7:, Folder 94)
  - Boiler 900-901: diagram, blueprint, instructions, notes, 1928-1929 (Box 7:, Folder 95)
  - Boiler 901: blueprints, drawings, diagrams, 1942-1954 (Box 7:, Folder 96)
  - Boiler 901 #2 Local Service Transformer: notes, undated (Box 7:, Folder 97)
  - Boiler 901 #1 Local Service Transformer: notes, undated (Box 7:, Folder 98)
  - Boiler 902: notes, instructions, parts data, diagrams, blueprints, drawings, requisitions, purchase orders, various dates (Box 7:, Folder 99)
  - Boiler 902-903: Cottrell (Rappers) instructions, printed material, diagrams, blueprints, packing lists, correspondence, invoices, notes, 1929-1970 (Box 7:, Folder 100)
  - Boiler 902-903: New Rectifiers (Cattrell) diagrams, assignment sheets, 1963-1971 (Box 7:, Folder 101)
  - Boiler 903: notes, drawings, blueprints, printed material, diagrams, 1939-1954 (Box 7:, Folder 102)
  - Boiler 903: Cattrells diagrams, drawings, diagrams, correspondence, invoices, 1933-1969 (Box 7:, Folder 103)
  - Boiler 904: diagrams, blueprints, drawings, notes, ampere meters, printed material, instructions, 1940-1953 (Box 7:, Folder 104)
  - Boiler 904: Cattrell (Rappers) diagrams, correspondence, invoices, notes, printed material, 1944-1956 (Box 7:, Folder 105)
  - Boiler 904: Cattrell and Substation blueprints, diagrams, instructions, printed material, parts lists, notes, research data, correspondence, various dates (Box 7:, Folder 106)
  - Boilers 905, 906, 907 and related: diagrams, 1979 (Box 7:, Folder 107)
  - Coal Lorries: drawings, blueprints, notes, ca. 1954 (Box 7:, Folder 108)
  - Coal Lorries: Stokers blueprints, 1929 (Box 7:, Folder 109)
  - Unit Heaters: Washroom, Boiler Room, Storehouse instructions, notes, 1941-1942 (Box 7:, Folder 110)